Guide to the Christine M. Golde Committee Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Christine M. Golde committee records
1991-2001
SC0925
Golde, Christine M.
1 Linear feet
These files were generated during her work for several Stanford committees when she was a graduate student, 1992-93, including the Provost’s Committee on Recruitment and Retention of Women Faculty. Other topics include budget matters, statistics on graduate students, and graduate student funding. Materials include memos, minutes, notes, statistics, newsletters, handbooks, and clippings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Christine M. Golde earned her AM in sociology at Stanford in 1993 and her Ph.D. in education in 1996. In 1995 she received a James W. Lyons Award for Service for her dedication to improving services for graduate students. She is currently Associate Vice Provost for Graduate Education at Stanford University.
Description of the Collection
These files were generated during her work for several Stanford committees when she was a graduate student, 1992-93, including the Provost’s Committee on Recruitment and Retention of Women Faculty. Other topics include budget matters, statistics on graduate students, and graduate student funding. Materials include memos, minutes, notes, statistics, newsletters, handbooks, and clippings.
Access Terms
Golde, Christine M.; Stanford University. Office of the Provost. Committee on Recruitment and Retention of Women Faculty.; Graduate students.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Graduate students statistics 1991-95 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Graduate students statistics by major program 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Graduate students statistics – applications to degree programs 1984-92 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student statistics (general) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Incremental masters 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Humanities and Sciences memos re graduate student issues 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Graduate student expense budgets 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Graduate student 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Graduate Student Handbook 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meetings with University officials 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meetings with students - notes (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Golde’s memos re work for the President’s office, Summer 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Biological Sciences, Ph.D. information (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - English department, Ph.D. information (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Geological and Environmental Sciences, Ph.D. information (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History Department, graduate student handbook (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Graduate students, miscellany (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Provost’s Committee on Recruitment and Retention of Women Faculty, agenda and minutes, 1992-93 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Provost’s Committee on Recruitment and Retention of Women Faculty, miscellaneous correspondence and information (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Provost’s Committee on Recruitment and Retention of Women Faculty, subcommittees (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Provost’s Committee on Recruitment and Retention of Women Faculty, press coverage of Report, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Provost Search Committee 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Trustees, information (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Tuition remission 1992-93 (Box 2, Folder 12)